so if we divide a circle into even more smaller pieces
you can see that every time
the shape becomes more like a rectangle
so how small was we divide a circle
before we can get a perfect rectangle
well we can keep on doing the circle into small
smaller or the smallest pieces you can make
but the answer is to divide the circle infinitely
many times until we can distinguish the lines
and eventually
the circle can now become the perfect rectangle
so the area of the circle
is equal to the area of the rectangle
which is equal to base times height
the height of the rectangle
as you can see
is the same as the radius
so height is equal to radius
to find the base
we need to look at the circumference of the circle
and when we compare the base on the circumference
we can see that the base is equal to
1/2 the circumference
remember that the circumference is equal to 2 by R
when we combine with 1/2
the 2 is canceled out
and base is equal to by R
so now base times height becomes pi r times r
Combine the r together and we have pi r squared
which is equal to the air of the rectangle
which is equal to the air of the circle